Finding Aid for Delta Pi Epsilon. Kappa Chapter (University of Michigan) records, 1946-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Delta Pi Epsilon, Kappa Chapter (University of Michigan) records 1946-1998
Delta Pi Epsilon. Kappa Chapter (University of Michigan).
1.5 linear ft. and 1 oversize volume
9981 Bimu 2
Kappa Chapter of Delta Pi Epsilon established in 1946, part of national business education honor graduate society. Kappa Chapter dissolved in 1999. Minutes, membership material, financial records, and scrapbooks.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Kappa Chapter of Delta Pi Epsilon in June 1999, (Donor no. 8838 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
On July 23, 1946, the Kappa chapter of Delta Pi Epsilon, a national business education honor graduate society, was installed at the University of Michigan. Delta Pi Epsilon encouraged members to further professional development in their field, through research, leadership, and service. These goals were pursued by actively encouraging research, developing leadership responsibilities, promoting service to the community, and improving relations between business schools and businesses. With the assistance and guidance of their sponsor and mentor, Professor John M. Trytten, head of the Business Education department, the Kappa chapter at the University of Michigan pursued these objectives.
The chapter initially met monthly to discuss both problems and discoveries in the business education field. This allowed them to plan projects and programs that incorporated new innovations. At conferences, leadership retreats, and lectures, they explained their work and demonstrated their findings for other educators to incorporate in their teachings. In their own community, members gave lectures and promoted research and service by awarding scholarships in the business education field.
As business education at the University Michigan changed, the chapter moved to at-large status in 1981. By the late 1990s, membership had dropped off considerably. With the lack of interest and aging members, Kappa Chapter of Delta Pi Epsilon dissolved in May 1999.
The records of the Kappa Chapter of the Delta Pi Epsilon society have been divided into series of Administrative, Correspondence, Initiation and Membership, Audio Materials, and Photographs and Scrapbooks.
Subjects:
Delta Pi Epsilon. Kappa Chapter (University of Michigan); Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Business education.; University of Michigan--Honorary societies.; University of Michigan. School of Business Administration.
- Administrative
  The Administrative series contains meeting minutes of the Kappa chapter and the Inter-chapter council meetings, financial records, research foundation recognition awards, and information on the John and Frances Trytten Fund. These records detail the operation of the chapter, from the gathering of dues, to the research sponsored and pursued for scholarship.
  - Meeting Minutes, 1950-1991, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Monthly Reports, 1952-1955 (Box 1)
  - Inter-chapter Council Meetings, 1968, 1970, 1976, 1980, 1984-1985, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Financial
    - Budgets and Reports, 1954, 1956-1979, 1985-1986, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
    - Household Records
      - Membership and Initiation fees, and Delta Pi Epsilon Foundation contributions, 1981-1991 (Box 1)
      - Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1957-1980 (Box 1)
  - Research Foundation Certificates of Recognition, 1994-1995, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - John and Frances Trytten Fund, 1977-1992 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  Correspondence spans from 1946 to 1998, covering the entire scope of the Kappa Chapter. It details the communication between members, discussing chapter business and exchanging ideas.
  - 1946-1992, 1998, 8 folders (Box 1)
- Initiation and Membership
  Initiation and Membership records are comprised of correspondence and information for/from members. They include membership update information, initiation records, and correspondence regarding membership and initiation.
  - Initiation and Membership fee payments, 1962, 1990-1994, 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Initiation Correspondence, 1961, 1967, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
  - Membership Forms (Box 1)
  - Membership Update Information, C.1955 1967, 1971 (Box 1)
- Audio Materials
  The Audio Materials file consists of two audio tapes. They are from the 35th anniversary celebration of the Kappa Chapter in 1981.
  - Audio Recordings from 35th Anniversary Celebration, 1981 (Box 1)
- Photographs and Scrapbooks
  Photographs and Scrapbooks span from 1946 to 1986. It is composed of materials that detail the history of Kappa Chapter with photographs and other mementos saved by chapter members throughout the years.
  - Photographs from convention in Mt. Pleasant, 1991 (Box 2)
  - 35th Anniversary Celebration scrapbook, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1971 (Box 2)
  - Historian's Scrapbook, 1946-1952 (Volume 1)